Guide to the Edgar Eugene Robinson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Publications
  - Publications by Robinson, Dec 1906-Dec 1908 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Publications by Robinson, Jan 1909-Dec 1928 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Publications by Robinson, Jan 1929-Dec 1934 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Publications by Robinson, Jan 1935-to date (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Publications by Robinson. (Fragments and, Undated) (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Herbet Hoover: President of the United States. Manuscript, 1958 (Box 74)
  - Herbet Hoover: President of the United States. revised manuscript, 1961-63 (Box 75)
  - Correspondence: J. P. Lippincott, publishers (Box 75)
  - Correspondence re: Herbert Hoover, 1952-75 (Box 76)
  - reviews re: Herbert Hoover (Box 76)
  - Notes re: Herbert Hoover (Box 77)
  - Presidential Power in the Nuclear Age House Document no. 298, 90th Congress 2nd Session pp. 58-64, reprint from Powers of the President in Foreign Affairs, 1945-65, pp. 245-251 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - The Tradedy of Leadership, reprinted in The New Deal Doctrine and Democracy, edited by Bernard Sternsher, 1966. pp. 185-196 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - A New American History, 2-Feb-46 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - The Place of Party in the Political History of the United States, 1928 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Twenty Years of Independent Study at Stanford University, 1945 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - The Independent University and the Volunteer, An address given at the Decennium Luncheon of the Stanford Associates on, April 11, 1945 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - American Democracy in time of Crisis, October 1, 1934 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Argument for the Bok Peace Plan, printed in Transactions of the Commonwealth Club of California vol. XIX no. 2, pp. 119-125, April, 1924 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Statement for Section on International relations printed in Transactions of the Commonwealth Club of California vol. XIV no. 4, pp. 98-105, May 1919 (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - An Observer's Impressions of the Conference printed in Transactions of the Commonwealth Club of California vo. XVII no. 2, pp. 72-81, April 1922 (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - The Legendary Roosevelt from the book The Roosevelt Leadership: 1933-1945, 1955; reprinted in Myth and the American Experience volume two by Nicholas Cordi and Patrick Gerster, pp. 271-275 (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - An Unaccustomed Road from The Roosevelt Leadership, 1955; reprinted in The New Deal What Was It? edited by Morton Keller, 1963, pp. 36-46 (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - The Constitution and American Democracy. An address before the Commonwealth Club of California, 12-Dec-37 (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - Can Democracy Survive the War? America's Answer. An address before the Commonwealth Club of California, 7-Aug-42 (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - The Political Significance of the United States in the world (The Long War Against Communism). An address before the Commonwealth Club of California, July 21, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - The Commonwealth, vol. LXXI no. 26, shows E. E. Robinson was a member of the Governor's Club of 1977, 5-Sep-77 (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - The Man on the Frontier printed in Annual contest of the Northern Oratorical League, 1908, pp. 45-50 (Box 86, Folder 17)
  - Plaque: The Commonwealth Club of California in recognition of Distinguished Service to the Club, Presented to Professor Edgar E. Robinson, 20-Dec-63 (Box 86, Folder 18)
  - Powers of the President in Foreign Affairs 1945-1965, 1966 (Box 86, Folder 19)
  - Herbert Hoover: President of the United States, 1975 (Box 86, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, pamphlets, correspondence (Box 86, Folder 21)
  - Powers of the President in Foreign Affairs 1945-1965, 1966 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - The Presidential Vote 1896-1932, 2nd printing, 1947 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - The Presidential Vote 1896-1932, reprinted, 1970 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - They Voted for Roosevelt - The Presidential Vote 1932-1944, 1947 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - They Voted for Roosevelt - The Presidential Vote 1932-1944, reprinted, 1970 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - The Evolution of American Political Parties, 1924 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - The Roosevelt Leadership 1933-1945, 2nd printing, 1972 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Independent Study in the Lower Division at Stanford University 1931-1937 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - The Evolution of American Political parties, 1924 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - They Voted For Roosevelt - The Presidential Vote 1932-1944, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Scholarship and Cataclysm - Teaching and research in American History 1939-1945, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - The New United States, 1946 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - The Roosevelt Leadership 1933-1945, 1955 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - The Presidential Vote 1896-1932, 1934 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - reviews (Box 88, Folder 8)
- Diaries, 1900-1979
  - 1900-1904 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - 1904-1908 (Box 63)
  - 1908-1928 (Box 64)
  - 1929-1935 (Box 65)
  - 1936-1941 (Box 66)
  - 1942-1950 (Box 67)
  - 1951-1954 (Box 68)
  - 1955-1959 (Box 69)
  - 1960-1965 (Box 69B)
  - 1966-1969 (Box 69C)
- Personal Correspondence
  - 1904 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - 1905 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - 1906 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - 1907 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - 1908 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - 1909 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - 1910 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - 1911 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - 1912 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - 1913 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - 1914 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - 1915 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - 1916 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - 1917 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - 1918 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - 1919 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - 1920 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - 1921 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - 1922 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - 1923 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - 1924 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - 1925 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - 1926 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - 1927 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - 1928 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - 1929 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - 1930 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - 1931 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - 1932 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - 1933 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - 1934 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - 1935 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - 1936 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - 1937 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - 1938 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - 1939 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - 1940 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - 1941 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - 1942 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - 1943 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - 1944 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - 1945 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - 1946 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - 1947 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - 1948 (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - 1949 (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - 1950 (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - 1951 (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - 1952 (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Unsorted family letters (Box 70-72)
- Miscellaneous Papers
  - Edgar Eugene Robinson, Teacher (tribute upon retirement) (Box 73)
  - Herbert Hoover Oral History Program: Interview with Dr. Edgar E. Robinson (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Oral Memoir of Edgar E. Robinson, typescript transcript part 1, 90 pages (Ancestry, Childhood, Preparation for college, University of Wisconsin, Teaching at Carleton College, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Oral Memoir of Edgar E. Robinson, typescript transcript part 2, 132 pages (Morning at Stanford), 1967 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings re. Robinson (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Transfer of Property on Salvatierra; Purchase of Property on Cabrillo (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - List of Early Publications (Box 89, Folder 6)
- Audiorecordings, Accession ARCH-1982-109
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 1: A. Childhood - From Birth to Joel Robinson and Niagara to 1901, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 1: A. Childhood - From Birth to Joel Robinson and Niagara to 1901 (Duplicate), 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 2: Preparation for College. College - University, 1904-1907, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 2: Preparation for College. College - University, 1904-1907 (Duplicate), 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 3: College [illegible], 1911, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 3: College [illegible], 1911 (duplicate), 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 4: 1st year at Stanford and beyond, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 5: Stanford during war; the presidency of Wilbur, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 6: [illegible], 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Edgar E. Robinson Memoirs - Tape 7: Retire to Stanford 1921-1926; Book on parties-early service for Hoover Library; Relations with Dr. Wilbur; Board of Trustees., 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-1986-112
  - Robinson's letters and diary entries re Herbert Hoover (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - reminiscences re Herbert Hoover, 1931-74 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Preliminary outline on Hoover presidencey, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Address on Hoover and the presidencey, Chit Chat Club, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous items re Herbert Hoover, 1936-83 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous papers and speeches, 1905, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sermon, "Spiritual Basis of the American Dream,", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Speech, re Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - reprints and articles by Robinson (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Information on Robinson House in Governor's Corner, Stanford University (dormitory complex) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-1991-149
  - Diaries, 1970-1975 (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth articles, 1938 and 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Death certificate, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - E.E. Robinson Professorship: clippings and correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Legal papers and estate matters (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Memorial book from his funeral, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Notes (on historical topics) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - School essay, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Historian, April 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Statement on F. D. Roosevelt's death, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Who's Who certificate, 1978/79 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and articles about Robinson (Box 3)
  - O'Callaghan, J., articles on mining (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - O'Callaghan, J., papers on public land policy (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Robinson, Lisette, correspondence with J. O'Callaghan, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Robinson, Lisette, correspondence with J. O'Callaghan, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Robinson, Lisette, general correspondence, 1977-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - White, Edward, Presidential Vote, typescript paper (to the memory of E.E.R.) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Potter, David M. The Background of the Civil War, reprint, autographed inscription (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bailey, Thomas A., America's Emergence as a World Power, reprint, autographed inscription, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Papers pertaining to Katherine Young Robinson, first wife of E.E. Robinson
    - Letters to E.E. Robinson, 1908-1927 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Telegrams to E.E. Robinson, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Letters to E.E. Robinson, circa 1921 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters to relatives, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters from E.E. Robinson, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters from E.E. Robinson, 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Letters from friends, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Journal, 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Journal, 1911-1913 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Journal, loose items, 1911-1913: (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Notebook with drafts of letters, essays, journal entries (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Essays, circa 1910 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Stories (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Wedding book, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Death certificate and funeral records (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Family (Young, Albrecht, Robinson) clippings and memorabilia (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Family correspondence, 1880-1926 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Family genealogy correspondence and papers (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Photographs
    - E.E. Robinson childhood (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - E.E. Robinson school portraits, 1900's (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Photographs, 1900's (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - E.E. Robinson portraits, 1910's (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, 1910's (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1920's (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - E.E. Robinson portraits, 1930's (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, 1930-1934 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Photographs, 1935-1939 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, 1940's (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, 1950's (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, 1960-1970's (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - E.E. Robinson portraits, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Photo album, pages 1-2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Photo album, pages 3-4 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Photo album, pages 5-6 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Photo album, pages 7-8 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Photo album, pages 9-10 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Photo album, pages 11-12 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Photo album, pages 13-14 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Photo album, pages 15-16 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Photo album, pages 17-18 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Photo album, pages 19-20 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Photo album, pages 21-22 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Photo album, pages 23-24 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Photo album, pages 25-26 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Photo album, pages 27-28 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Photo album, pages 29-30 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Photo album, loose items (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - E.E. Robinson's birthplace, Oconomowoc, WI (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - E.E. Robinson's high school mentor (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Photographs, K.Y. and E.E. Robinson (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Scrapbook pages on K. Young and E.E. Robinson (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - K. Young, up to age 17 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - K.Y. Robinson as young adult, portraits (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - K.Y. Robinson in later years, portraits (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - K.Y. Robinson's mother (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Wisconsin friends and family (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Family, 1880's-1890's (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Robinson family, 1960's-70's (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The cat (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - David Starr Jordan (Davey photograph) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ray Lyman Wilbur, signed (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Postcards (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Framed photographs of Katherine Y. Robinson, E.E. Robinson and parents of E.E. Robinson (?); and medals (Box 8)
    - Oversized photographs and membership certificate in Commonwealth Club, 1968 (Box 9 os)
  - Books by Edgar E. Robinson: (Box 7)
    - American Democracy in Time of Crisis, 1934
    - The Evolution of American Political Parties, 1924
    - The Foreign Policy of Woodrow Wilson 1913-1917, 1918
    - The New United States, 1946
    - The Population of California, 1946
    - The Presidential Vote 1896-1932, (Robinson's marked copy), 1934
    - The Roosevelt Leadership 1933-1945, (marked for corrections), 1955
    - Annual Contest of the Northern Oratorical League, (containing Robinson's entry The Man on the Frontier), 1908
  - Books presented to Edgar E. Robinson (inscribed): (Box 7b)
    - Bailey, Thomas A. Essays Diplomatic and Undiplomatic, 1969
    - Guerard, Albert. France; a Modern History, 1959
    - Hoover, Herbert. The Challenge to Liberty, 1934
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman. The March of Medicine
    - Vucinich, Wayne S. Serbia Between East and West; the Events of 1903-1908, 1954
    - The Journal of Captain John R. Bell; edited by Harlin M. Fuller and LeRoy R. Hafen, 1957
    - Wilson, Albert. These Were the Children, 1963
  - Diplomas of E.E. Robinson